<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  ~  Version: MPL 1.1/GPL 2.0/LGPL 2.1
  ~
  ~  "The contents of this file are subject to the Mozilla Public License
  ~  Version 1.1 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in
  ~  compliance with the License. You may obtain a copy of the License at
  ~  http://www.mozilla.org/MPL/
  ~
  ~  Software distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS"
  ~  basis, WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the
  ~  License for the specific language governing rights and limitations under
  ~  the License.
  ~
  ~  The Original Code is ICEfaces 1.5 open source software code, released
  ~  November 5, 2006. The Initial Developer of the Original Code is ICEsoft
  ~  Technologies Canada, Corp. Portions created by ICEsoft are Copyright (C)
  ~  2004-2006 ICEsoft Technologies Canada, Corp. All Rights Reserved.
  ~
  ~  Contributor(s): _____________________.
  ~
  ~  Alternatively, the contents of this file may be used under the terms of
  ~  the GNU Lesser General Public License Version 2.1 or later (the "LGPL"
  ~  License), in which case the provisions of the LGPL License are
  ~  applicable instead of those above. If you wish to allow use of your
  ~  version of this file only under the terms of the LGPL License and not to
  ~  allow others to use your version of this file under the MPL, indicate
  ~  your decision by deleting the provisions above and replace them with
  ~  the notice and other provisions required by the LGPL License. If you do
  ~  not delete the provisions above, a recipient may use your version of
  ~  this file under either the MPL or the LGPL License."
  ~
  -->

<renderer>
	<description>
	           <![CDATA[<p>The tree component displays hierarchical data as a "tree" of branches  and leaf nodes.
            Optionally, the tree may also display navigation controls for the dynamic expansion
            and collapse of branch nodes. Tree navigation events are available so that an application 
            can respond to these events. Nodes may also support an action event that can be used to respond
            to user click events. <br>
            
            The tree component can be used in cases where a hierarchical data structure must be viewed
            and navigated. It is typically used for menu-style applications, where the user selects
            a tree node and the application responds with an action related to the selected node.<br>
            
            In implementing a tree tag, the application developer must provide declare in the JSP a tree tag and 
            a single treeNode tag as a child of the tree tag. The tree tag should declare the "value" attribute
            to be a value binding to a backing bean that will return an object that implements the 
            javax.swing.tree.TreeModel interface. The TreeModel must contain a tree of DefaultMutableTreeNode instances.
            Each DefaultMutableTreeNode instance encapsultes an IceUserObject. The IceUserObject is the extension point
            for the application developer. If the IceUserObject does not provide sufficient state for representation
            of the tree's nodes, then the application developer should extend the IceUserObject and add state as required 
            to their extension. When creating an IceUserObject, the DefaultMutableTreeNode wrapper must
            be provided to the constructor. Then the node's state can be set to the attributes on the IceUserObject including:
            text, a convenience field that will typically represent the text that will be displayed somewhere 
            in the content facet; expanded, whether the node is expanded on its first rendering and until the 
            user initiates a navigation event to change this value; tooltip, the text that will appear in the 
            tooltip that appears when the user hovers over a node; leafIcon, the application-relative path to 
            an image that will be used to represent this node when it has no children (is a leaf),
            typically referred to in the icon facet; branchExpandedIcon, the application-relative path to 
            an image that will be used to represent this node when it has children (is a branch) and is expanded,
            typically referred to in the icon facet; branchContractedIcon, the application-relative path to 
            an image that will be used to represent this node when it has children (is a branch) and is not expanded,
            typically referred to in the icon facet. The "binding" attribute can be defined so that the 
            application developer will have access to the Tree component in the application's backing bean.
            The "var" attribute can be declared on the tree tag such that the treeNode tag's children have 
            access to the state of the TreeModel's node that it represents.<br>
            See the documentation for the treeNode tag for a description of supported facets.]]>
	</description>
	<component-family>com.icesoft.faces.TreeView</component-family>

	<renderer-type>com.icesoft.faces.View</renderer-type>

			<renderer-extension>
				<instance-name>tree</instance-name>
				<is-container>true</is-container>
				<renders-children>true</renders-children>
				<tag-name>tree</tag-name>
				<taglib-prefix>@taglib-prefix@</taglib-prefix>
				<taglib-uri>@taglib-uri@</taglib-uri>
			</renderer-extension>

</renderer>
